let quiz=[
    {
      question: "Chola Empire was divided into :",
      option: [
           "Mandalams, Nadu, Kurram & Valanadu ",
           "Mandalams, Nadu, Malkhand & Avanti",
           "Mandalams, Bhoomi, Avanti & Valanadu",
           "Mandalams, Nadu, Kurram & Malkhand",
      ],
      answer: 1,
    },
    {
      question: "For which period did Harihara Raya II of Sangama dynasty ruled the Vijaynagara :",
      option: [
           "1446-1465",
           "1485-1491",
           "1491-1505",
           "1377-1404",
      ],
      answer: 4,
    },
    {
      question: "The traces of Janapadas and Mahajanpadas are found in ___ :",
      option: [
           "Vedic text",
           "Buddha text ",
           "Jaina text",
           "All of the above",
      ],
       answer: 4,
    },
    {
      question: "Which one of the following was the capital of Kosala :",
      option: [
           "Sravasti",
           "Shuktimati",
           "Kaushambi",
           "Indraprastha",
      ],
      answer: 1,
    },
    {
      question: "Champa was the capital of which one of the following Mahajanapadas in Ancient India :",
      option: [
           "Anga",
           "Magadha",
           "Vajji",
           "Kasi",
      ],
      answer: 1,
    },
    {
      question: "Bimbisara was the founder of which one of the following dynasties :",
      option: [
           "Nanda",
           "Haryanka",
           "Maurya",
           "Shunga",
      ],
      answer: 2,
    },
    {
      question: "A Janapadin was the ___ of a Janapada",
      option: [
           "Servant",
           "Minister",
           "Army Ruler",
           "Ruler",
      ],
      answer: 4,
    },
    {
      question: "What was the time period of Indus Civilisation/Harappan Civilisation :",
      option: [
           "2400BC-1700BC",
           "2500BC-1700BC",
           "2400BC-1750BC",
           "2500BC-1750BC",
      ],
      answer: 4,
    },
    {
      question: "Which one of the following was an important Port of the eastern coast during Gupta period :",
      option: [
           "Kalyan",
           "Tamralipti",
           "Sopara",
           "Baroch",
      ],
      answer: 2,
    },
    {
      question: "The temple of Konark was built by Narasimha of the :",
      option: [
           "Maratha Administration",
           "Chola Administration",
           "Ganga Administration",
           "Vijayanagar Administration",
      ],
      answer: 3 ,
    },

    {
  question: "Who among the following Kushan Emperor was the first to introduce the Gold Coinage in India ?",
  option: [
  "Vima Kadphises",
  "Vima Taktu",
  "Vasishka ",
  "Kujula Kadphises",
  ],
  answer: 1, 
},
{
  question: "The daughter who milks animals in the Vedic Period was known as :",
  option: [
  "Kubha ",
  "Duhitr",
  "Komi",
  "Sardha",
  ],
  answer: 2, 
},
{
  question: "Megasthenes was succeeded as ambassador by :",
  option: [
  "Darius",
  "Demetirus",
  "Deimachos",
  "Philip",
  ],
  answer:  3, 
},
{
  question: "Which of the following Kushan Kings , who assumed the title - THE LORD OF THE WHOLE WORLD  ?",
  option: [
  "Kadphises I",
  "Kadphises II",
  "Kanishka",
  "Huvishka",
  ],
  answer: 2, 
},
{
  question: "Bimbisara was succeeded by :",
  option: [
  "Ashoka",
  "Ajatashatru",
  "Vasudeva",
  "Chandragupta Maurya",
  ],
  answer: 2, 
},

    ]
